lloydstsb-offshore.com 2016-06-16

# Privacy policy - Lloyds Bank International - Lloyds International

__Looking after your information

The UK Data Protection Act 1998, the Data Protection (Jersey) Law 2005, the Data Protection (Bailiwick of Guernsey) Law 2001, the Isle of Man Data Protection Act 2002 and the Gibraltar Data Protection Act 2004 (together the ‘Data Protection Regulations’) require Lloyds Banking Group companies to manage personal information in accordance with the principles contained therein. In particular, our Group of companies is required to process your personal information fairly and lawfully. This means that you are entitled to know how we intend to use any information you provide. You can then decide whether you want to give it to us in order that we may provide the product or service that you require. Lloyds Banking Group requires all employees to maintain customer confidentiality in accordance with the Data Protection Regulations. We provide training and education to all employees to remind them about their obligations.

 __Where we obtain your information

Your personal information will be held securely in Lloyds Banking Group systems (including systems in the UK) so that we and any other companies in our Group that you have dealings with, either now or in the future, can manage your relationship with us. This will include information you provide when you apply to us, and any additional information provided by you or others in various ways, including:

  1. in applications, emails and letters, during telephone calls and conversations in branch, when registering for services, in customer surveys, when you participate in competitions and promotions, when using Lloyds Banking Group company websites, and during financial reviews and interviews;
  2. from analysis (for example, the amount, frequency, location, origin, and recipient) of your payments and other transactions, and your use of services involving other Lloyds Banking Group companies and what they know from operating your account (including the creation of profiles used to uniquely identify you when you use our online, mobile and telephony services) which are used to help us combat fraud and other illegal activity; and
  3. information Lloyds Banking Group companies receive from or through other organisations (for example card associations, credit reference agencies, insurance companies, retailers, comparison websites, social networks, and fraud prevention agencies) whether in the course of providing products and services to you or otherwise, and from information we gather from your use of and interaction with our internet and mobile banking services and the devices you use to access them. 

We will not retain your personal information for longer than is necessary for the maintenance of your account, or for legal or regulatory requirements.

 __How we share your information

We may share the personal information we hold about you across the Lloyds Banking Group (which includes companies in the UK) for the following administrative activities:

  1. providing you with products and services and notifying you about either important changes or developments to the features and operation of those products and services;
  2. responding to your enquiries and complaints;
  3. administering offers, competitions, and promotions;
  4. undertaking financial reviews; and
  5. facilitating the secure access to online platform;  
and also for the following data sharing activities:
  6. updating, consolidating, and improving the accuracy of our records;
  7. undertaking transactional analysis;
  8. arrears and debt recovery activities;
  9. testing new systems and checking upgrades to existing systems;
  10. crime detection, prevention, and prosecution;
  11. evaluating the effectiveness of marketing, and for market research and training;
  12. customer modelling, statistical and trend analysis, with the aim of developing and improving products and services;
  13. assessing lending and insurance risks across the Lloyds Banking Group; and
  14. managing your relationship with the Lloyds Banking Group companies.

By sharing this information it enables us, and other companies in the Lloyds Banking Group, to better understand your needs and run your accounts in the efficient way that you expect.

Your data may also be used for other purposes for which you give your specific permission, or, in very limited circumstances, when required by law or where permitted under the terms of the Data Protection Regulations.

 __When we may share your information

We will treat your personal information as private and confidential, but may share it with each other and disclose it outside the Lloyds Banking Group if:

  1. allowed by this agreement;
  2. you consent;
  3. needed by our agents, advisers or others involved in running accounts and services for you or collecting what you owe Group companies;
  4. needed by subcontractors to help us manage your records;
  5. taxing or other authorities require it;
  6. the law, regulatory bodies, or the public interest permits or requires it;
  7. required by us or others to investigate or prevent crime;
  8. needed by market research companies to assist us in providing better products and services for you
  9. to any other parties connected with your account (including guarantors); or
  10. required as part of our duty to protect your accounts.

We will always ensure your information remains safe and secure.

 __Sharing your information with other companies

If you were ‘introduced’ to us by a third party and/or have a relationship with or are supporting one of our affinity partners (e.g. a charity credit card account), we will give them your contact details and sufficient information about you to help with their accounting and administration. Introducers or affinity partners may use these details to contact you about products and services unless you have asked them not to do so.

 __Using your information to help prevent terrorism and crime

We are also required to comply with regulatory requirements to screen applications that are made to us to ensure we are complying with the international fight against terrorism and other criminal activities. As a result of this we may need to disclose information to government bodies.

 __Sharing your information to assist with asset buying or selling

Lloyds Banking Group companies may in the future wish to sell, transfer or merge part or all of their business or assets, or any associated rights or interests, or to acquire a business or enter into a merger with it. If so, they may disclose your personal information to a potential buyer, transferee, or merger partner or seller and their advisers so long as they agree to keep it confidential and to use it only to consider the possible transaction. If the transaction goes ahead, the buyers, transferee or merger partner may use or disclose your personal information in the same way as set out in this statement.

 __Sharing your personal information with card providers

If you hold a credit or debit card with us, we will share transaction details with our scheme providers (e.g. Visa or Mastercard).

 __Searching insurance records

If you apply to us for insurance, we will pass your details to the insurer. If you make a claim, any information you give to us, or to the insurer, may be put onto a register of claims and shared with other insurers to prevent fraudulent claims. A list of the participants is available from the insurer. We may also disclose your information within our group of companies, to our agents and other insurers to investigate or prevent fraud.

 __Sharing your personal information between 1st and 2nd charge lenders

If you have a secured loan or mortgage with us, we may need to share information with other lenders who also hold a charge on your property.

 __Joint Applicants

If you give personal information about someone else (such as a joint applicant) then you should not do so without their permission. Where information is provided by you about someone else, or someone discloses information about you, it may be added to any personal information that is already held by us and it will be used in the ways described in this privacy statement.

 __Sharing personal details between joint applicants

Sometimes, when you open a joint account or product, this may mean that your personal data will be shared with the other applicant. For example, transactions made by you will be seen by your joint account holder and vice versa.

 __How we manage sensitive personal information

The Data Protection Regulations define certain information as ‘sensitive’ (racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious beliefs, trade union membership, physical or mental health, sexual life, criminal proceedings and offences). If you apply to us for insurance, a pension, health insurance, life assurance or investment advice, we may ask you for some ‘sensitive’ details. We will only use this information to provide the service you require and we will ask for your explicit consent. As a customer, there may be times when you give us sensitive information. We may share it with other Lloyds Banking Group companies and our subcontractors to keep your records up to date.

 __How we manage information collected on statements

Some transactions that you or additional card holders make on a card account may cause sensitive or confidential details to appear on your statement. By using your card to make such transactions you give us your explicit consent to process this information.

 __Using companies to process your information outside the EEA

All countries in the European Economic Area (EEA), which includes the UK, have similar standards of legal protection for your personal information. We may run your accounts and provide other services from centres outside the EEA (such as the USA and India) that do not have a similar standard of data protection laws to the UK, Channel Islands, Isle of Man or Gibraltar. If so, we will require your personal information to be protected to at least UK, Channel Islands, Isle of Man or Gibraltar standards. We may process payments through other financial institutions such as banks and the worldwide payments system operated by the SWIFT organisation if, for example, you make a CHAPS payment or a foreign payment. Those external organisations may process and store your personal information abroad and may have to disclose it to foreign authorities to help them in their fight against crime and terrorism. If these are based outside the EEA, your personal information may not be protected to standards similar to those in the UK, Channel Islands, Isle of Man or Gibraltar.

 __Using credit scoring

When you apply for credit, an automated system known as credit scoring may be used when considering whether to agree the borrowing. It is a method of assessing your likely conduct of an account based on a range of data, including the conduct of previous similar accounts. It is a system widely used by credit providers to help make fair and informed decisions on lending.

Credit scoring takes account of information from three sources - the information you provide on your application, information provided by credit reference agencies and information that may already be held about you by companies in the Lloyds Banking Group. A credit scoring system will consider information from these sources, to make an overall assessment of your application.

The credit scoring methods used are regularly tested to ensure they remain fair, effective and unbiased. Using a credit scoring system helps our Group companies to lend responsibly. If you submit an application and it is declined through this automated process, you can contact us within 21 days to have the decision reconsidered. You also have the right to ask that the decision is not made based solely using a credit scoring system.

 __How we use Credit Reference Agencies

Credit Reference Agencies (CRAs) collect and maintain information about consumers' and businesses' credit behaviour. This includes Electoral Register, fraud prevention, and credit information - including details of previous applications and the conduct of your accounts - and public information such as County Court judgements, decrees, and bankruptcies.

The information that Lloyds Banking Group companies and other organisations provide to CRAs about you, your financial associates and your business (if you have one) may be provided to other organisations and used by them and us to:

  1. help make decisions, for example when 
    1. checking details on applications for credit and credit-related or other facilities;
    2. managing credit and credit-related accounts or facilities;
    3. recovering debt;
    4. checking details on proposals and claims for all types of insurance; and
    5. checking details of job applicants and employees;
 
  2. detect and prevent crime, fraud and money laundering;
  3. check your credit history;
  4. verify your identity if you, or someone financially linked with you, applies for services;
  5. trace your whereabouts; and
  6. undertake research, statistical analysis and systems testing.

If a Lloyds Banking Group company needs to make a credit decision when you apply for a credit-based product or service (e.g. mortgage, personal loan, credit card, or current account) or to review the amount of credit it provides under an existing agreement, such as an overdraft, your records will be searched, along with those of anyone who is financially associated with you such as your spouse or partner. The CRA will keep a record of this search and place a "footprint" on your credit file, whether or not the application proceeds.

We may give details of your account and how you conduct it to CRAs, including if you borrow and do not repay in full and on time. If you fall behind with your payments and a full payment or satisfactory proposals are not received within 28 days of a formal demand being issued, then a default notice may be recorded with the CRAs. Similar information may also be given about your other lending/credit relationships with members of our Group. Any records shared with CRAs will remain on file for 6 years after your account is closed, whether it has been settled by you or as a result of a default. Other organisations may see these searches and updates if you apply for credit in the future, and these may affect your ability to borrow from other lenders.

If you apply for or hold an account in joint names, or tell us that you have a spouse or financial associate, a financial association will be created between your records, including any previous and subsequent names used by you. This means that your financial affairs may be treated as affecting each other. These links will remain on your and their files until such time as you or your spouse or financial associate is successful in applying for a disassociation with the CRAs to break that link. You must be sure that you have their agreement to disclose information about them. Searches may be made on all joint applicants, and search footprints will be left on all applicants’ records.

You have a right to apply to the CRAs for a copy of your file.

We carry out most of our credit searches using Experian, but details of how you have run your account(s) may be disclosed to all CRAs. The information they hold may not be the same and there is a small fee that you may need to pay to each agency that you apply to. The addresses for the CRAs used in the Channel Islands and Isle of Man are detailed below, or, if you are resident elsewhere, please contact us.

For Channel Islands and Isle of Man their addresses are:

  * Experian Consumer Help Service, PO Box 9000, Nottingham NG80 7WP or call 0344 481 8000 or log on to [www.experian.co.uk](http://www.experian.co.uk/ "www.experian.co.uk")
  * Equifax plc, Credit File Advice Centre, PO Box 1140, Bradford BD1 5US or log on to [www.equifax.co.uk](https://www.equifax.co.uk/ "www.equifax.co.uk")
  * CallCredit, Consumer Services Team, PO Box 491, Leeds LS3 1WZ or call 0870 060 1414 or log on to [www.callcredit.co.uk](http://www.callcredit.co.uk/ "www.callcredit.co.uk")

For Jersey and Guernsey we may also use the following:

  * Integricheck Limited, 3 Le Clos Des Blanches, St Clement, Jersey, JE2 6PB. Telephone: 01865 461533 

__Using Fraud Prevention Agencies

We have systems that protect our customers and ourselves against fraud and other crime. Customer information can be used to prevent crime and trace those responsible. We will share your personal information from your application with fraud prevention agencies. If false or inaccurate information is provided and fraud is identified, details of this fraud will be passed to these agencies. Law enforcement agencies may access and use this information. We and other organisations may also access and use this information to prevent fraud and money laundering, for example, when:

  * checking details on applications for credit and credit related or other facilities;
  * managing credit and credit related accounts or facilities;
  * recovering debt;
  * checking details on proposals and claims for all types of insurance; and
  * checking details of job applicants and employees.

Please contact us on **0345 602 7174** if you want to receive details of the relevant fraud prevention agencies. We and other organisations may access and use from other countries the information recorded by fraud prevention agencies.

 __How we check your identity

We may ask you to provide physical forms of identity verification when you open your account. Alternatively, we may search CRA files in assessing your application. The agency also gives us other details and information from the Electoral Register to verify your identity. The agency keeps a record of our search, whether or not your application proceeds. Our search is not seen or used by lenders to assess your ability to obtain credit.

 __Undertaking Anti-Money Laundering checks

To comply with money laundering regulations, there are times when we need to confirm (or reconfirm) the name and address of our customers. This information may be shared with other Lloyds Banking Group companies. For more details about identity checks, please contact us.

 __Credit searching directors

The Data Protection Regulations do not generally apply to companies but they do cover personal data relating to sole traders and partnerships. When we receive an application from a business we may perform a search with a CRA on the individual company directors or partners, or any guarantors.

 __Obtaining information about you, and other personal details

When you apply for a mortgage or further borrowing it may be necessary to obtain references, details of your existing financial commitments, and any other information that is required to assess or review lending risks, to recover debts, and to prevent or detect fraud. Where applicable, your current and previous employers, accountant, landlord, lender, bank, insurance or pension company may be contacted to obtain this information. In limited circumstances these references may need to be obtained after you open your account. This may be for regulatory purposes, or if the lending decision needs to be reviewed. Your permission to obtain these references will therefore continue to apply after your account has been opened. It may also be necessary to obtain information or documentation from your solicitor relating to any work they carry out either on your or our behalf.

 __Using your details for service contact

Making sure we deliver excellent customer service is very important to us and to do this various methods of communication may be used when sending you information about your account. Most of the time you will be contacted by letter or telephone, but you may also be sent updates by text message (where that service is available) or email when it is believed to be appropriate. You can ask us to stop sending these messages at any time. Additionally, in extraordinary circumstances (such as natural disaster or civil unrest) we may also send you updates by text message (where that service is available) or email. If we decide to use email to contact you, we will only do this if we have ensured that using email will not put your information at risk, or, if you have requested we email you, that we have explained the risks of sending an "insecure" email and that you are happy to accept that risk.

In addition you may wish to choose a channel of communication that suits you when you need to contact us. If you need to email a Lloyds Banking Group company, we recommend you check their website to see if a secure email facility exists so that your email can be sent securely. If you send us emails in other ways, such as from your personal account, then remember that the message may not be secure and there is a risk that it could be intercepted. If you choose to send an "insecure" email, please keep the amount of confidential information you include to a minimum.

 __Recording phone calls

We may monitor or record phone calls with you in case we need to check we have carried out your instructions correctly, to resolve queries or issues, for regulatory purposes, to help improve our quality of service, and to help detect or prevent fraud or other crimes. Conversations may also be monitored for staff training purposes.

 __Using information on social networking sites

As part of our ongoing commitment to understanding our customers better, we may research comments and opinions made public on social networking sites such as Twitter and Facebook.

 __Obtaining a copy of your information

Under the Data Protection Regulations you have the right of access to your personal data. The Data Protection Regulations allow us to charge a fee of £10 for this service. If anything is inaccurate or incorrect, please let us know and we will correct it. For further details on how to request a copy of your information, please contact:

  * For Gibraltar: Royal Ocean Plaza, Ocean Village, Gibraltar GX11 1AA
  * For Guernsey: PO Box 53, 1 Smith Street, St Peter Port, Guernsey, GY1 4BD
  * For Isle of Man: PO Box 111, Peveril Buildings, Peveril Square, Douglas, Isle of Man IM99 1JJ
  * For Jersey: PO Box 160, 25 New Street, St. Helier, Jersey JE4 8RG.

 __Using your personal information to contact you about products and services

Unless you have asked us not to, we and other Lloyds Banking Group companies may contact you by mail, telephone, email or text message (where that service is available) about products and services available from the Group. In addition we may also contact you about products and services from selected companies outside the Group, which we believe may be of interest to you or benefit you financially.

We promise not to contact you about everything - only if we think it could be appropriate and relevant to you, such as preferential savings opportunities, account upgrades or special offers. This contact may continue after your relationship with us ends. You may opt out of receiving this information at any time by calling us, writing to us or contacting your local branch.

 __Passing your information to other companies for their own direct marketing

Unless you have given us your consent, we will not provide information about you to companies outside our Group to use for their own marketing purposes.

 __Using cookies

In general, you can visit Lloyds Banking Group websites without identifying who you are or revealing any information about yourself. However, cookies are used to store small amounts of information on your computer, which allows certain information from your web browser to be collected. Cookies are widely used on the internet and do not identify the individual using the computer, just the computer being used. Cookies and other similar technology make it easier for you to log on to and use our websites during future visits.

Visit our [cookie notice page](http://international.lloydsbank.com/cookies/ "cookie notice page") for access to our cookie notice.

 __Viewing notifications

Organisations in the Channel Islands, Isle of Man and Gibraltar must lodge a notification with the Data Protection Commission in the relevant Channel Island or the Data Protection Supervisor in the Isle of Man, or the Gibraltar Regulatory Authority as appropriate, describing the purposes for which they process personal information. The details are publicly available from the relevant authority and you can view ours at:

  * Gibraltar: <http://www.gra.gi/data-protection/register-of-data-controller/registration>
  * Guernsey:[ www.gov.gg/dataprotection](http://www.gov.gg/dataprotection " www.gov.gg/dataprotection")
  * Isle of Man: [www.gov.im/odps](http://www.gov.im/odps/ "http://www.gov.im/odps/")
  * Jersey: <https://www.dataci.je/online-notification/#/search>

__Changes to privacy statement

  * We keep our privacy statement under regular review and we will reflect any updates within this statement. This privacy statement was last updated July 2015. 

September 2014  
“How we use Credit Reference Agencies”: The additional credit reference agencies that we may use in Jersey and Guernsey have changed as follows: TABS (Trades Advisory Bureau Services) and Chancellor’s Debt Recovery Limited are replaced with Integricheck. 

May 2015  
Remove company names: Lloyds Management (Channel Islands) Limited, Lloyds Trust Company (Channel Islands) Limited. 

July 2015  
To help us confirm your identity and protect your accounts, we’re improving the way we uniquely identify you based on how you use our Internet Banking service. We have updated the sections of our Privacy Statement that outline ‘where we obtain your information’ and ‘how we share your information’ to reflect changes.
